Quinn mss., 1896-1930 LMC 1859
Lilly Library
Quinn mss.
1896-1930
Lilly Library
Synge, J. M. (John Millington), 1871-1909
LMC 1859
1.6 linear feet 1 folder; 1 box; 1 volume; 81 items.
The Quinn mss., 1896-1930, contains the correspondence of dramatist John Millington Synge, 1871-1909; the final draft of his play, The Playboy of the Western World; and the writings of other authors, chiefly Amory Hare, 1885-1964.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
John Millington Synge, 1871-1909, was an Irish dramatist.
Amory Hare, 1885-1964, was a writer.
Mildred H. Quinn of Indianapolis, died 1964, was a relative of John Quinn, 1870-1924, lawyer, New York book collector, and patron of Irish letters.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into 2 fonds: John M. Synge and Other Authors.
These fonds are divided into 4 series: I. Correspondence; II. Play; III. Amory Hare; IV. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Content Note
The Quinn mss., 1896-1930, contains the correspondence of John Millington Synge, 1871-1909, dramatist; the final draft of his play, The Playboy of the Western World; and the writings of other authors, chiefly Amory Hare, 1885-1964, found in the possession of Mildred H. Quinn of Indianapolis at the time of her death in April 1964.
Related Material
See the Untermeyer mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana, for a letter from John M. Synge to Louis Untermeyer.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1964
Correspondence; Plays; photographs; Dramatists; Book collectors; Dramatists, Irish--20th century--Correspondence; Dramatists, Irish--20th century--Biography; Dramatists, Irish; Authors, Irish--19th century--Drama; Drama--19th century; Synge, J. M. (John Millington), 1871-1909; Hare, Amory, 1885-1964; Indianapolis (Ind.); Fraser, Claud Lovat, 1890-1921; Quinn, Mildred H., ? -1964
- John M. Synge
  - I. Correspondence
    Scope and Contents
    Folders are arranged chronologically.
    - Fraser, Claud Lovat. To "My dear sir", 1916, Apr. 12 (File 1)
    - 1896-1905 (Box 1)
    - 1906-1920 (Box 1)
    - 1921-1925 (Box 1)
    - 1926-1930 (Box 1)
    - n.d. (Box 1)
  - II. Play
    - The Playboy of the Western World final draft (Vault 1)
- Other Authors
  - III. Amory Hare
    - Folder 1 (Box 1)
      - Sung in the Street (Box 1)
    - Folder 2 (Box 1)
      - Moorings (Box 1)
      - Reprieve (Box 1)
    - Folder 3 (Box 1)
      - The 'Yuman Element' (Box 1)
      - Her Turn (Box 1)
      - Courage (Box 1)
      - Intimately Seen (Box 1)
    - Folder 4 (Box 1)
      - Poor Devil (Box 1)
      - Length of a Candle (Box 1)
      - Hammer & Thumb (Box 1)
      - The Toy (Box 1)
      - The Perfect Swindle (Box 1)
    - Folder 5 (Box 1)
      - As Wind to Wheat (Box 1)
      - Unsigned Letters (Box 1)
      - A Face at the Door (Box 1)
    - Folder 6 (Box 1)
      - Persons of No Importance (Box 1)
      - Loon's Laughter (Box 1)
      - From Beyond (Box 1)
    - Folder 7 (Box 1)
      - Posted as Missing (Box 1)
  - IV. Miscellaneous
    - Homes of Men (Box 1)
    - Pictures (Box 1)